<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-17T15:18:10+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Test note</title><link href="/2021/05/17/test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test note" /><published>2021-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2021/05/17/test</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/05/17/test.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;hello&quot;&gt;Hello!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a test note…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="note" /><summary type="html">Hello!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A bloat ride</title><link href="/2021/03/25/minweb.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A bloat ride" /><published>2021-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2021/03/25/minweb</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/03/25/minweb.html">&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:40%;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/minweb/wiby.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:200px;width:250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;A bloat ride through a day of HN articles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Call it &lt;em&gt;bloat&lt;/em&gt;, call it &lt;em&gt;inefficient&lt;/em&gt;, call it whatever you want. It doesn’t matter &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; it is described, users instinctively understand what is wrong with the modern web. 
Luke Smith recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cvDyQUpaFf4&quot;&gt;excommunicated&lt;/a&gt; recipe sites for taking up tens of megabytes of bandwidth for a single recipe - many of 
which contain relatively little text and image content. ~10MB sounds a pittance to a user of the modern web, where almost every article is rife with fancy javascript wizardry, 
pagination, and boatloads of other such bloatware*&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;. However, there are many, existing arguments (which are also more eloquent than mine) against the ever growing size of page weight -
that is, the size of web pages - such as Dan Luu’s article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://danluu.com/web-bloat&quot;&gt;restrictive web bloat for rural internet users&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;0&lt;/sub&gt; and Maciej Cegłowski’s 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://idlewords.com/talks/website_obesity.htm&quot;&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt; which jointly reveal that, regardless of the reasons behind said web bloat, the implementation of multi-megabyte webpages
both serves little purpose and consequently restricts access a to given webpage. To demonstrate the problem, I’m going to take a leaf out of Maciej’s book and pick some articles and webpages at random and take a look at their page weight. Infact, if you take anything away
from this post, I hope it is that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; should go away and try this for yourself. Only upon doing so will you realise that this is not a cherry-picking exercise and, rather, is a real phenomenon that
 authors and web-devs know about but cannot seem to (or do not want to) resolve. But first, let’s talk about some &lt;em&gt;averages&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a few &lt;em&gt;average&lt;/em&gt; figures about the web that are quite surprising: The median webpage size is &lt;a href=&quot;https://httparchive.org/reports/page-weight&quot;&gt;over 2MB&lt;/a&gt;, the average time
to render a webpage fully is over &lt;a href=&quot;https://backlinko.com/page-speed-stats&quot;&gt;10 seconds&lt;/a&gt; on desktop and double that on mobile clients. Unsurprisingly, the average connection 
speed worldwide was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.akamai.com/us/en/multimedia/documents/report/q3-2015-soti-connectivity-final.pdf&quot;&gt;~5Mbps&lt;/a&gt; in 2015 - note that speeds have most likely improved since 2015.
What does this all culminate to? An averagely shitty experience accessing the modern web. The &lt;em&gt;average&lt;/em&gt; modern website is optimised for the &lt;em&gt;average&lt;/em&gt; user*&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, this works in theory as internet speeds 
and mobile data packages increase in volume year-on-year*&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;. However, this cuts off a specific kind of user, the user with slow internet, a minimal data package, 
or both of these things - this, as Dan Luu points out, usually means people living in the developing world or in rural areas*&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;. Keep this in mind as we move forward, I don’t think any of the
following examples would be impossible to load via a satellite link in Ethiopia, but Dan gives a few examples of sites that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; probably use every day that are either borderline-impossible or literally
impossible to load and use via a rural internet link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at some examples. Firstly, I’ll copy Maciej’s approach and ridicule a &lt;a href=&quot;https://fetchprofits.com/website-code-bloat/&quot;&gt;particular example&lt;/a&gt; of an article that discusses how website bloat can
negatively impact your traffic and, thus, conversions - marketing lingo for getting lurker plebians to buy your wares. The article, which, without edits to the spacing, can fit comfortably on three sides of A4, tells
 people how to reduce bloat whilst weighing in at a chunky ~4MB, reduced to 2.77MB with NoScript (a Firefox utility to block Javascript), and further to 1.79MB when viewed in reader view 
(CTRL+ALT+R on Firefox, if you are somehow unaware). The obvious reason for this is the infographic taken from &lt;a href=&quot;https://skilled.co/resources/speed-affects-website-infographic/&quot;&gt;Skilled.co&lt;/a&gt; which,
 as far as I’m concerned, could be replaced with a link - this would further cut the page weight (without Javascript) to less than 1MB. This might &lt;em&gt;sound&lt;/em&gt; like an improvement but this is still 846 bytes per
word. To put this kind of page bloat into perspective, again, borrowing from Maciej, David Foster Wallace’s &lt;em&gt;Infinite Jest&lt;/em&gt;, one of the longest English novels ever written, has 543,709 words, and is still
lighter (~1.5MB in EPUB, ~3MB in PDF) that this webpage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next few examples are pulled from a hour-or-so browse of HackerNews for blog-like articles, all of them are, in my opinion, &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; bloated given their content. Ben Evans’s 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ben-evans.com/benedictevans/2021/3/14/do-amazon-ads-bring-in-more-cash-than-aws&quot;&gt;article on Amazon’s income&lt;/a&gt; is 3.31MB without Javascript blocking. This article fits onto less than two sides of A4, 
yet is still over a megabyte without any Javascript, the culprit here is a 900KB CSS file assumedly from a Squarespace theme. Jacques’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://jacquesmattheij.com/piano-practice-software-progress/&quot;&gt;update on his piano practice software&lt;/a&gt;
 is ~2.5MB. Honestly, this isn’t as egregious as some of the following
examples because, besides an uncompressed (or unstripped) PNG file (~300KB), the bloat in this case comes solely from the embedded YouTube player which will request over 2MB in scripts per embedded video. A better 
example of where this gets really overwhelmingly inefficient really quickly is Softology Blog’s 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://softologyblog.wordpress.com/2017/03/28/more-fun-with-lattice-boltzman-method-lbm-fluid-simulations/&quot;&gt;discussion of Lattice Boltzman Method fluid simulations&lt;/a&gt;
which contains four embedded videos, 2MB for each, 8.4MB total webpage size. Javascript, usually for overly-smart features or tracking cookies, tends to be the reccurent villain in the search for web bloat.
Hackaday articles - as interesting as they tend to be - such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.io/project/6150-beckman-du-600-reverse-engineering/log/50756-discovering-a-new-vga-mode&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; by Joe Zatarski are always
larger than a megabyte due to what I can only assume is useless background Javascript, running NoScript the page becomes 763KB (down from 1.3MB without any noticable changes) with the only problem remaining being a 661KB CSS file. 
Medium is a platform that has a particular knack for filling their articles to the brim with useless crap, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-bad-influence/your-addiction-to-outrage-is-ruining-your-life-9effebdfeaca&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; by Pete Ross 
weighs in at an obese 4.66MB - the article itself is fairly short and can be read in reader view for only 5.42KB. At first glance you may think the large cover image is the cause of the problem but you would be somewhat incorrect,
 whilst the image is an overly large 290KB, removing useless scripts with NoScript reduces the page size by 85%. I did find an article on HN containing &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; Javascript, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pudding.cool/2021/03/foundation-names/&quot;&gt;this interesting article&lt;/a&gt;
by Ofunne Amaka and Amber Thomas, whilst not about anything I really care about, contains interactive elements, pagination, and all the traditional blog-style scripting at a size that subceeds the previous Medium article - 
3.22MB with scripts (150KB without) - but has a valid (and quite attractive) use case that requires its inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:10%;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/minweb/deargod.png&quot; style=&quot;width:909px;height:297px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;blockquote&gt;
                &lt;blockquote&gt;
                  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s something seemingly absent from the above article…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;/blockquote&gt;
              &lt;/blockquote&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
        &lt;/blockquote&gt;
      &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News outlets are akin to Medium in that they overuse copious amounts of Javascript and unaltered images leading to a laughable page weight to text content ratio. Here are some I, again, pulled from HN: 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spectator.co.uk/article/the-beauty-of-the-ampersand-and-other-keyboard-symbols&quot;&gt;This Spectator article&lt;/a&gt; by Hodgkinson should demonstrate the hideous nature of web bloat better than any other
example in this post, without NoScript the page is an absolute mammoth, a 740 word essay that just about fits on a single side of A4, weighing in at 7.65MB (humorously, this means that you’re taxed 10KB for every
word read). The scripts, in this case (as is true for most media outlets on the modern web), are semi-malicious in nature. Along with the tracking cookies we’ve all come to know and despise, is a gigantic footer
 that does not (yet) block the user from reading the article but declares boldly and obstructivley that we’ll soon be stopped from viewing articles on the site - which is probably a good thing if we’re viewing 
via a satellite or tariffed internet connection. Chopping out the javascript removes all of this fluff but what remains is two &lt;em&gt;gigantic&lt;/em&gt; images (568KB and 516KB respectively) and 800KB worth of CSS, what a waste.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/mar/28/chevron-lawyer-steven-donziger-ecuador-house-arrest&quot;&gt;This Guardian article&lt;/a&gt; is a little bit better, 500KB when all the tracking cookies and pop-ups are blocked, 
you’re getting a word every 300 bytes or so here. But enough with the semi-bloated examples, we want the big chonkers, the most insane examples. Enter 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-29/nomura-says-it-may-have-significant-loss-from-u-s-operations&quot;&gt;a Bloomberg article about Nomura&lt;/a&gt;, by the time you click through to the article itself, you’ve
received ~13MB of data to read a 280 word article containing a cover image and single graph. Similarly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/28/22351901/bmw-high-beam-assist-assistant-dlc-paid-update-ota&quot;&gt;this article on the Verge&lt;/a&gt;
contains 299 words of original content but clocks in at almost 12MB of data, including our old friend the YouTube embedded player (which cannot be blocked by NoScript), even without the unnecessary scripts, the page
has a ratio of 10KB for every word. Lastly is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt; whose news articles tend to focus on visuals (which then get licensed to every other European news outlet) which would be fine if their
site didn’t use a Javascript gallery rather than embedded images, forcing readers to soak up 3-6MB per article or read without images (both NoScript and reader view strips images from the articles).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt; What can be done? &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was originally envisioned due to my recent obsession of viewing random webpages via &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiby.me/&quot;&gt;Wiby&lt;/a&gt;. Wiby is a search engine that indexes websites that have low page weights and little-to-no
scripting, it calls this “classic web”. The idea behind the tool is great, however, there’s not enough websites indexed currently for it to be of use to anyone (in my opinion - if you use the tool for a few minutes
you will probably feel the same way). Despite this, there’s a number of interesting websites indexed on Wiby including &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eskimo.com/~scs/cclass/cclass.html&quot;&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mlab.uiah.fi/~eye/demos/&quot;&gt;hobbyists&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.waldeneffect.org/&quot;&gt;outdoorsy people&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://rickadams.org/adventure/&quot;&gt;indoorsy people&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gerlofs.me/&quot;&gt;great looking websites&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://easydos.com/&quot;&gt;eyesores&lt;/a&gt; of the internet. I don’t advocate
anyone drop DDG and use Wiby or another minimal website index, rather, the entire charm of Wiby and similar indexing systems (including those who chain their blogs together into a little sub-web) is that it shows there is 
a group of intelligent individuals who care about the web-obesity problem and are attempting to find their own solutions*&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;. I have compiled some ideas that may or may not be constructive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;1: You can compress images and remove metadata to reduce their size. A PNG of a giant ampersand shouldn’t be half a megabyte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:40%;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/minweb/help.png&quot; style=&quot;width:151px;height:244px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;2: Reduce your script size by cutting out unnecessary javascript and reducing reliance on libraries. Your blog doesn’t need tracking cookies. 
You do &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; need to import jquery into your DOM to swap between &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/how-to-create-dark-light-mode-for-website-using-javascript-jquery/&quot;&gt;light mode and dark mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;3: Replace embedded scripts (such as the embedded YouTube player) with reasonable alternatives if removing it from the page would not significantly alter the quality of the page. For example,
there’s no reason why any of the above examples could not replace the embedded player with a static string or image linking (in another tab) to the YouTube video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;4: Stop using blogging platforms that allow you to do none of the above. Setting up a website is easy, there are guides on the internet about HTML and CSS, this is all you need to make a 
personal blog or simplistic site - using templating software or blog platforms is tempting but can result in pointlessly bloated websites*&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;5: You can’t avoid bloatware sites, so get NoScript (or a similar JS blocker) and an ad-blocker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;6: If you find a blog you like, add it to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thesitewizard.com/faqs/howtoreadsitefeeds.shtml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; and build up a subscription portfolio of small, informative sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no happy ending to this ride. Unless search engines started allowing users to search by page weight, I don’t really forsee an easy solution to the continuing problem of web bloat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Appendix/Footnotes:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;0&lt;/sub&gt; Note that one of Dan’s examples is &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.codinghorror.com/&quot;&gt;codinghorror&lt;/a&gt; (no pun intended, I guess), one of the most egregious examples of web bloat in a blog site, 45.15MB!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; Here’s a comprehensive list: tracking ads, cookie pop-ups, pointless embedded youtube clips that &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be linked to, hunkering slabs of CSS with no &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; purpose, any javascript that is
completely irrelevant to the serving of the article I am currently reading, and uncompressed images containing metadata such as XMP, IPTC, colour profiles, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; You will notice that I neglected to correct my own point here, the average &lt;em&gt;worldwide&lt;/em&gt; user isn’t actually the one that web developers design their webpages for, no no, as you will find out, the target
audience of these bloated pages actually have far-above-average connection speeds which increase in speed year-on-year, covering up the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; The median internet speed in the United Kingdom is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastmetrics.com/internet-connection-speed-by-country.php#median-internet-speeds-2020&quot;&gt;28.51Mbps/8.87Mbps&lt;/a&gt; 
(up/down), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ofcom.org.uk/research-and-data/telecoms-research/broadband-research/may-2020-uk-home-broadband-performance&quot;&gt;less than 30%&lt;/a&gt; of connected households have &amp;lt;30Mbps, and 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ofcom.org.uk/research-and-data/telecoms-research/broadband-research/may-2020-uk-home-broadband-performance&quot;&gt;20%&lt;/a&gt; of the populace currently do not have a broadband connection. These stats are 
generally inline with &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of Europe (I should note that whilst mean speeds are higher in much of Western Europe, median speeds paint a different picture) and, in terms of 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ofcom.org.uk/research-and-data/multi-sector-research/infrastructure-research/connected-nations-2018/interactive-report&quot;&gt;coverage&lt;/a&gt;, most regions have a high availability of broadband (without
regard for speed) - interestingly, the county I reside in has one of the worst coverage statistics in the country. Much of the discussion around internet speeds within the UK (in recent years) has centered
around whether people can effectively use streaming services or not, yet many people still have sub-par connection speeds and can barely access and use &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; modern websites due to issues with both 
speed and usage limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Keep in mind that people in the continental US and elsewhere are still on dial-up connections, &lt;a href=&quot;https://1-minute-modem.branchable.com&quot;&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt; even documented what this experience is like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; Using a service to find the page weight before you open a page does not seems to be a work-around to this issue if you are on a bandwidth restricted connection as this doesn’t usually return the actual
size of the page with scripts and images included nor does it provide an optimal alternative - I believe this is something that could be benefitial to people given the problem of web bloat doesn’t seem to be subsiding 
over a short span of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Haha but you use Jekyll for static side generation, hello mr. bloatman!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="post" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kodibox</title><link href="/2021/03/21/kodibox.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kodibox" /><published>2021-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2021/03/21/kodibox</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/03/21/kodibox.html">&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left:40%;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/project/kodi/kodibox.jpg&quot; style=&quot;height:200px;width:250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;Go stream-less for under $200&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Weapon of choice:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kodi.tv/&quot;&gt;Kodi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adapted from:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media Experience’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://mediaexperience.com/raspberry-pi-xbmc-with-raspbmc/&quot;&gt;Guide&lt;/a&gt; to LibreELEC &amp;amp; Kodi on RBP4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Summary:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many UK-based taxpayers, I don’t like or need the TV license. For years I have been connecting my old Macbook to the television and using the 
contemporary streaming solutions - Netflix and the like (I don’t &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; I need to discuss why these streaming services are terrible for the consumer*&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;)
I decided to replace this solution with something a little smaller and more energy efficient: A Raspberry Pi (RBP from now on) running the popular open-source &lt;em&gt;Kodi&lt;/em&gt; 
software and LibreELEC operating system. This isn’t &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; of a project but I thought it would be useful to share a more condensed guide than the one linked above with
 some extra pieces of information I gained along the way…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how to build a small media center for less than £200*:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt; Parts List: &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Raspberry Pi 3/4.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A RBP power-supply (~5V, 3A).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A micro-SD card.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A micro-HDMI to HDMI cable (or an adapter &amp;amp; HDMI cable).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An on/off USB-C switch (optional).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A RBP case (optional).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An external HDD or SSD (optional).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt; How do? &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build the case and fit the RBP, this part &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be fairly obvious if you have a good quality case.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re opting to use Kodi for media files (e.g. DVD rips), an external hard drive can be loaded up and connected to the RBP Kodi box. Ensure the 
drive is formatted to NTFS or ext4 or it won’t be usable with the RBP.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re planning on using WiFi with the RBP (e.g. for the Kodi remote app), mess with your router to stop the RBP from occupying the 5GHz band - the
wifi on the RBP is terrible enough without the reduced range/penetration.*&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt; Appendix: &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; There’s an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/blakemorgan/2019/02/19/what-is-the-netflix-effect/?sh=ca883e56409b&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in Forbes about how Netflix is bound to destroy traditional TV and cinema
because it’s giving consumers what they want, and what do they want? Supposedly they want &lt;em&gt;“products that are easy to use and tailored to match their preferences”&lt;/em&gt;, which, I suppose, is true but that description
certainly doesn’t suit Netflix in its current state. If you’ve never had the pleasure, Netflix is easy to use if, and only if, you’re open to consuming specific programming without much thought. It’s a bundle of
 both popular releases and in-house, barely passable movies and series that are selectively added and removed at will with little warning given to the user. Owing more to the &lt;em&gt;Spotify effect&lt;/em&gt; than anything else,
it also lacks any real form of useful user recommendations other than giving you more of the same thing and plastering the service with its own releases as often as possible.
There are other &lt;a href=&quot;https://mubi.com/&quot;&gt;services&lt;/a&gt; that offer a more movie-centric approach with an &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; selection process. It is also difficult and, I would argue, unreasonable, to ignore the point that the typical
 consumer &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; really &lt;strong&gt;care&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; they spend their money when it comes to media, in order to decide who they give their money to, rather than pay for the convenient approach and allow Netflix to decide how to
 split the pot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; This is a guide price that assumes an external drive is being used. I opted for a 5TB HDD which pushed the cost of this project up to ~£165.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; I had some issues with audio playback via the micro-HDMI output, this can be resolved by tunneling into the RBP and adding &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;hdmi_drive=2&lt;/code&gt; to the 
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/flash/config.txt&lt;/code&gt; file. More information on this can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.libreelec.tv/thread/20621-no-audio-on-hdmi-from-new-pi4b-a-common-prob-it-seems/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, one of the micro-HDMI ports
doesn’t support audio playback, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; In fact, the WiFi on RBP4 is such a joke - with issues ranging from WPA authentication, to the 5GHz band, to screen resolution in &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/assortedhackery/status/1200056633898029061&quot;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt;
than one &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.libreelec.tv/thread/21096-rpi4-can-t-use-wifi-network-error-input-output-eror/&quot;&gt;case&lt;/a&gt; - I would just recommend not using it if possible. I’m using the Kodibox as a glorified, offline, media center so 
this is not really an issue in my case.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="unlisted" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Greplike</title><link href="/2021/02/05/grep.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Greplike" /><published>2021-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2021/02/05/grep</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/02/05/grep.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding-left:35%;height:25%;width:25%;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/project/grep.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;A regular expression engine and string-matching tool&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gerlofs/greplike&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Written in:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adapted from:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greplike is an extension of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/beautiful-code/9780596510046/ch01.html&quot;&gt;Pike’s regular expression matcher &lt;/a&gt; and is, thus, also inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://swtch.com/~rsc/regexp/&quot;&gt;Russ Cox’s series on regular expressions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Summary:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Greplike&lt;/em&gt; is the first project in a series surrounding compiler design. Compilers use a lexical analysis step - see: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Introduction-Compiler-Undergraduate-Computer-Science/dp/3319669656&quot;&gt;Mongensen’s introduction&lt;/a&gt;
for more information - which requires a regular expression engine to parse plain-text to tokens. In order to correctly write this component, knowledge of regular expressions and pattern matching is required. &lt;em&gt;Greplike&lt;/em&gt; is a black-box
re-write of the &lt;em&gt;grep&lt;/em&gt; tool using concepts outlined by Pike and Kernighan in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Practice-Programming-Professional-Computing/dp/020161586X&quot;&gt;The Practice of Programming&lt;/a&gt;. The tool is a somewhat-less-efficient*&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, 
non-finite-automata version of grep, that builds upon Pike’s initial sub-100 sloc engine whilst applying many of the improvements outlined in the subsequent discussion by Kernighan (linked to in the &lt;em&gt;Adapted From&lt;/em&gt; section).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Greplike&lt;/em&gt; is a rudimentary, toy, pattern-matching tool that can be used, &lt;em&gt;like grep&lt;/em&gt;, for parsing through files to find occurances of a string using literals or a regular expression. Unlike the &lt;em&gt;grep&lt;/em&gt; tool, &lt;em&gt;greplike&lt;/em&gt;
has some limitations including a lesser number of command-line and engine options available. For example: the user cannot invert the search using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-v&lt;/code&gt; or ignore case using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-y&lt;/code&gt; 
(greplike is &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; case-sensitive), and the user may not select a set of regular expressions to use (with &lt;em&gt;grep&lt;/em&gt; this can be done with the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-p&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-e&lt;/code&gt; flags for PCRE and extended sets).
Greplike uses a sub-set of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Regular_Expressions/POSIX_Basic_Regular_Expressions&quot;&gt;POSIX Basic Regular Expressions&lt;/a&gt; which does not (currently*&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;) support the following
meta-characters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;}&lt;/code&gt; (braces) used for matching a preceeding character/group/class &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; times.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[^&lt;/code&gt; used for matching characters &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; within the suffix class, e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[^abc]&lt;/code&gt; matches everything besides &lt;em&gt;abc&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;POSIX class categories (e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[:upper:]&lt;/code&gt; for all uppercase characters).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally greplike does not support metacharacters inside groups of classes (e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;(a+b+c)+d&lt;/code&gt; is not a valid regular expression in greplike).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Using the tool:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a limited number of options available in &lt;em&gt;greplike&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-f&lt;/strong&gt;: Define a list of files to parse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-e&lt;/strong&gt;: Define a regular expression to serve as a matching set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-n&lt;/strong&gt;: Print the line number of each successful match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-i&lt;/strong&gt;: Print the filename of the file in which a match was found.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-c&lt;/strong&gt;: Count and subsequently print the number of matching occurences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;General case:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;./greplike &amp;lt;expression&amp;gt; &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Match with line numbers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;./greplike -f &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt; -e &amp;lt;expression&amp;gt; -n&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Testing:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bash scripts are located in the &lt;em&gt;/tests/&lt;/em&gt; folder, there are five test cases*&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Valid tests: A set of valid expressions are run against a single file full of randomised text (ASCII only).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invalid tests: A set of invalid expressions are run against the above file, all should fail with a return code != 0.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Single-file test: A set of files and expressions are used as greplike arguments, for each the return code should be 0.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multi-file test: A set of expressions are run against all three files (dummy&lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;.txt), each should return code 0.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Timing test: The above test is run using grep and greplike, the times are returned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Appendix:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; | I, currently, have no plans to keep &lt;em&gt;greplike&lt;/em&gt; up-to-date and implement upon the documented functionality. As stated, &lt;em&gt;greplike&lt;/em&gt; was an exercise in learning about string parsing, and
regular expressions. There will be an finite-automata-centric version which is required for the lexical parsing stage of a compiler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; | I say this because, as Cox discusses, expression matching parsers &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be horrifically inefficient in certain edge cases due to backtracking. Backtracking is, essentially, 
a quality that arises in certain types of algorithmic problems such as constraint statisfaction problems (e.g. a sudoku solver) in which a successful
approach is based upon a condition that can sometimes be partially valid (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Mastering-Regular-Expressions-Powerful-Techniques/dp/1565922573&quot;&gt;Friedl&lt;/a&gt;
 presents the expression &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;to(nite|knight|night)&lt;/code&gt; as an example, where testing and removing two of the three 
invalid options is required). A backtracked approach requires a variable to be stored (in this case the regular expression string) that can be reverted-to in a scenario where a partial match
eventually results in being invalid (e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tonighz&lt;/code&gt; will not match &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;to(nite|knight|night)&lt;/code&gt; until the very last character check).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; | I have plans to flesh out this testing to include checks for number of matches and possibly shift this over to python or some other language to write a test harness, this
isn’t a priority though.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>